A Guide to Jane Bowles Papers 1966-1967
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Jane Bowles Papers 1966-1967
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11037
37 items
The papers, beonging to the publisher's original file for the play A Quarreling Pair, contain correspondence, in-house memoranda, a photograph of Truman Capote and Bowles, the manuscript, dust jacket, and reviews.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This item was purchased by the Library from Ken Lopez Bookseller, of Hadley, Mass., on May 26, 1992.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of thirty-seven items, 1966-1967, all belonging to the publisher's original file for the play A Quarreling Pair, which was first published in Mademoiselle a week before the play was included as the only original piece in The Collected Works of Jane Bowles, published by Farrar, Straus & Giraux, Inc. in December, 1966. The collection contains correspondence between Mademoiselle and Farrar, Straus and Giraux concerning serial rights; in-house memoranda concerning publication; the manuscript, carbons, and tearsheet copies of Truman Capote's introduction with photographs of Capote and Bowles; manuscripts and galleys of the play including copy editor's modifications; dust jacket; promo sheet; and reviews of the book.
Contents List
- Correspondence between Mademoiselle and Farrar, Straus & Giraux, Inc. concerning the purchase of First North American Serial rights to A Quarreling Pair1966 Aug 2-Sep 1, 6 TLS & TL
- Mademoiselle in-house memoranda concerning the possible publication of A Quarreling Pair by Jane Bowles 1966 Aug 9-16, 5 TLS & ALS
- "Introduction" to The Collected Works of Jane Bowles by Truman Capote 1966, photostatic copy, 4 p., TMs
- "Introduction" to The Collected Works of Jane Bowles by Truman Capote 1966, 3 TMs (C), 9 pages each
- "Truman Capote Introduces Jane Bowles" and A Quarreling Pair A Puppet Play by Jane Bowles in Mademoiselle1966 Dec
  8 printed tearsheet copies of the pieces as published, with photographs of Capote and Bowles
- A Quarreling Pair A Puppet Play by Jane Bowles 1966, 3 TMs (C)
- A Quarreling Pair A Puppet Play by Jane Bowles 1966, galleys
- A Quarreling Pair A Puppet Play by Jane Bowles, an edited electrostatic copy of the galley sheets with the copy editor's modifications specified 1966, galleys (EC)
- The Collected Works of Jane Bowles Dust Jacket and Promotional Sheet 1966
- Reviews of The Collected Works of Jane Bowles 1966-1967, 7 printed